cannondale.com 2019-07-27

# Privacy Policy - Dorel Sports

Last Updated: July, 2019  
This website (referred to herein as the “Site”) is operated by a company (referred to herein as “we“ or “us“) within the Dorel Sports group of companies. The relevant Dorel Sports company that is responsible for your personal information will be the Dorel Sports company that you provided your personal information to. For more information about the Dorel Sports group of companies and brands, or the specific Dorel Sports company responsible for your personal information, please see [https://www.dorelsports.com](https://www.dorelsports.com/) or contact us using the contact details listed below. If you would like details about how your personal information is processed in relation to the Cannondale Mobile App, visit the [Cannondale Mobile App Privacy Notice](https://www.cannondale.com/en/International/app-privacy-policy).

We recommend that you read this Privacy Policy in full to ensure you are fully informed. However, if you only want to access a particular section of this Privacy Policy, then you can click on the relevant link below to jump to that section.

**  
Information We May Collect  
Use and Sharing of Information Collected  
Legal basis for processing personal information  
Children  
Cookies, web beacons, and online advertising  
Social Network Access  
Security  
International data transfers  
Data retention  
Third-Party Sites  
Your data protection rights  
Changes and Updates  
**

**_Information We May Collect_**  
When you visit the Site, our servers capture the IP addresses, domain names and network identifiers of our users. In some countries, including those in the European Economic Area, this information may be considered personally identifiable information under applicable data protection laws. This information is aggregated to measure the number of visits, average time spent on the Site, pages viewed, and other similar usage information. We use this information to measure the use of our Site and to improve the content of our Site.

E-mail addresses and other personally identifiable information such as first and last name, home or other physical address, telephone number and other similar information are known only when voluntarily provided by a visitor for registration of product purchase, newsletters and communications, sweepstakes, contests or other participation of visitors in any available online interactive activities.

**_Use and Sharing of Information Collected_**  
Unless otherwise disclosed during its collection, personally identifiable information that may be collected in connection with visitors to this Site is retained by us or our parent, subsidiaries, or sister companies (“Affiliates”). We and our Affiliates do not sell, transfer or otherwise disclose this personally identifiable information outside those companies, except as disclosed below or where disclosure is required by law.

We may use the personal information you provide for any of the following purposes: (1) to contact product owners in response to product recalls, (2) to understand the use of our Site and make improvements; (3) to fulfill prizes; (4) to respond to specific requests from visitors; (5) to obtain parental consent from visitors under 18 years of age (or the applicable age of majority if higher in a particular jurisdiction), where necessary; (6) to provide any necessary notices to our visitors or their parent or guardians, where necessary; (7) to protect the security or integrity of our Site when necessary; (8) to send you notices and solicitations regarding the Site, our products or our Affiliates; (9) to share with authorized retailers and distributors of our products to promote our products to you, and (10) in general to promote and market our products and/or products of our Affiliates to you.

We also may share personal information with third parties for the following purposes:

  * to provide us with services in connection with the purposes listed above, such as website hosting, professional services (including information technology services and related infrastructure), customer service, shipping of items you order, auditing and other similar services necessary to the operation of the Site and services you request. In such cases, the information will be shared for the purpose stated, and not for independent use by the service provider.
  * in connection with an actual or potential corporate reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock.
  * to any competent law enforcement body, regulatory, government agency, court or other third party where we believe disclosure is necessary (i) as a matter of applicable law or regulation, (ii) to exercise, establish or defend our legal rights, or (iii) to protect your vital interests or those of any other person; and
  * to any other person with your consent to the disclosure.

**_Legal basis for processing personal information_**  
Our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it.

However, we will normally collect personal information from you only (i) where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you, (ii) where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your rights, for example to tailor our marketing to you, or (iii) where we have your consent to do so. In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you or may otherwise need the personal information to protect your vital interests or those of another person.

If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contact with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal information).

If we collect and use your personal information in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), these interests will generally relate to: operating our platform and communicating with you as necessary to provide our services to you, responding to your queries, improving our platform, undertaking marketing, or for the purposes of detecting or preventing illegal activities. We may have other legitimate interests and if appropriate we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are.

If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal information, please contact us using the contact details provided below.

**_Children_**  
It is our policy that visitors to our Site who are under the age of 18 (or applicable age of majority if higher in a particular jurisdiction) should not post on or provide information to our Site without the consent of their parents. You should supervise the online activities of your children, and consider the use of parental control tools available from online services and software providers that help provide a kid-friendly Internet environment. The Site is not intended for children under the age of 13. We will not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have obtained any personally identifiable information about a children under age 13, we will delete that information.

**_Cookies, web beacons, and online advertising_**  
A technology called “cookies” may be used to provide you with tailored information. A “cookie” is a tiny element of data that a Website can send to your browser, which may then be stored in your browser so we can recognize you when you return. Further information about how we use cookies and similar tracking technology can be found in our Cookie Notice.

**_Social Network Access_**  
If you sign in or link to the Site through any social networking service, such as Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, You Tube, and other services, any information you supply (or have supplied) to us becomes subject to the privacy policy of that social network/service. We do not control, and are not responsible for, the privacy practices of such networks or services. You should consult the privacy policy of such networks/services.

**_Security_**  
This Site has technical and organizational security measures in place. Some of the measures we use in different circumstances are encryption, secured entry points to our servers, and monitoring and training for our personnel to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. However, no system is perfect or can guarantee that unauthorized access or theft of information will not occur.

**_International data transfers_**  
Your personal information may be transferred to, and processed in, countries other than the country in which you are resident. These countries may have data protection laws that are different to the laws of your country.

Specifically, some of our Site servers are located in the United States, and our group companies and third party service providers and partners operate around the world. This means that when we collect your personal information we may process it in various countries.

However, we have taken safeguards to require that your personal information will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy. These include implementing the European Commission’s Standard Contractual Clauses for transfers of personal information between our group companies. We have also implemented safeguards with our third party service providers and partners. Further details, and copies of the standard contractual clauses can be provided upon request.

**_Data retention_**  
We retain personal information we collect from you where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so for example, to provide you with a service you have requested, to retain your information for future marketing purposes or to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements.

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

**_Third-Party Sites_**  
This Site may contain links to other sites of third parties. We are not responsible for the content of those websites or the privacy practices of those other sites or sites that they, in turn, may link to.

**_Your data protection rights_**  
If you are a resident of the European Economic Area, or in certain other situations, you have the following data protection rights, which you can exercise by contacting us using the details below:

  * The right to **access, correct, update or request deletion** of your personal information.

  * The right to **object to processing** of your personal information, ask us to **restrict processing** of your personal information or **request portability** of your personal information.

  * The right to **opt-out of marketing communications** we send you at any time. You can exercise this right by clicking on the “unsubscribe” or “opt-out” link in the marketing e-mails we send you. Alternatively, you can indicate your marketing preferences for email, phone and postal marketing during registration or at any time by contacting us using the contact details provided below.

  * The right, if we have collected and processed your personal information with your consent, to **withdraw your consent** at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.

We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

You also have the **right to complain to a data protection authority** about our collection and use of your personal information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority.

**_Changes and Updates_**  
We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we update our Privacy Policy, we will take appropriate measures to inform you, consistent with the significance of the changes we make. If you do not agree with the policy, you should cease use of the Site immediately. You can see when this Privacy Policy was last updated by checking the “last updated” date displayed at the top of this Privacy Policy.

If you have any questions or concerns about our use of your personal information, please contact us using the following details:

Office of the General Counsel, Attn: Privacy Compliance Counsel

1 Cannondale Way

Wilton, Connecticut 06897, United States of America

Telephone: (+1) 203.845.8300

Email: dataprivacy@dorelsports.com
